<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Brandon Davis</title><link>https://subdavis.com/</link><description>Recent content on Brandon Davis</description><generator>Hugo</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Sun, 23 Nov 2025 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://subdavis.com/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Thinking about Generative AI</title><link>https://subdavis.com/posts/2025-11-generative-ai/</link><pubDate>Sun, 23 Nov 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://subdavis.com/posts/2025-11-generative-ai/</guid><description>&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Long before we get to the point where a machine is a moral agent, we will have machines that are capable of suffering. - Ted Chiang&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I want to write out some thoughts to revisit later. It can be easy to get revisionist about what you believed and when, so here is a list of things I thought were true in late 2025 after ~2 years of pretty extensive experience with frontier models, especially Anthropic&amp;rsquo;s Claude.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id="some-takes"&gt;Some takes&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;AI is alarmingly good at all sorts of things. It is good at writing code, dealing with legal documents, talking through household repairs, and many other tasks.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We are not in a bubble comparable to previous bubbles, but the market is overheated. Many participants will suffer when their bad bets fail. A sector-wide collapse followed by another &amp;ldquo;AI winter&amp;rdquo; is not likely, but a recession that affects regular American families feels very possible.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Environmental concerns about AI and data centers can be &lt;a href="https://andymasley.substack.com/p/individual-ai-use-is-not-bad-for"&gt;pretty misleading&lt;/a&gt;. Environmental harms are important to mitigate, but environmental advocates seem overly focused on data centers compared to their relative impact or the marginal cost of reducing that impact.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As the US government actively sabotages renewable energy infrastructure projects, power demands from AI companies is both &lt;a href="https://investors.constellationenergy.com/news-releases/news-release-details/constellation-meta-sign-20-year-deal-clean-reliable-nuclear"&gt;applying positive pressure toward renewable energy transition&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href="https://stateimpactcenter.org/insights/data-centers-straining-the-grid-and-your-wallet"&gt;keeping fossil fuel plants online longer&lt;/a&gt; than they otherwise would be.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Using AI to produce art, especially that which supplants human artists, is bad. Artists have a unique and important role in a healthy society. It&amp;rsquo;s clear that this is already happening, and I&amp;rsquo;m very worried about it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Playing around and making art for personal use or amusement is mostly benign, though.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;AI boosters are pretty universally untrustworthy. Most of the experts on this technology have conflicts of interest, and their incentives are not aligned with public good. We need more independent experts outside the AI industry.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;AI skeptics often confuse material debates about the merits and capabilities of AI systems with larger philosophical or moral debates about capitalism. These are both important, but conflating them can result in motivated reasoning.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;AI will, in the near term, accelerate wealth inequality. Skeptics are correct about this. Longer term effects depend on what we decide to do as a society.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;AI will cause (mostly psychological) harm to humans at higher rates than other digital technologies. It will make harms from social media or smartphone use seem quaint. Society will mostly tolerate these harms and ignore them, just as it ignores the 1 million annual worldwide deaths from automobiles (40,000 in the US).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Large language models are not on the cusp of becoming self-aware or developing the capacity to suffer, but &lt;a href="https://alleninstitute.org/news/one-of-worlds-most-detailed-virtual-brain-simulations-is-changing-how-we-study-the-brain/"&gt;I am still worried that we might cause machines to experience suffering in the future.&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We have avoided nuclear holocaust thus far by luck. Nuclear disarmament should be an urgent priority. All sides of the AI discourse should agree on this.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h2 id="disclaimers"&gt;Disclaimers&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Qualifiers like &amp;ldquo;maybe&amp;rdquo; or &amp;ldquo;likely&amp;rdquo; were omitted because I am uncertain about everything, and otherwise I would have placed them everywhere. My goal was to stake out some positions, not hedge against being wrong.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I am neither a skeptic nor a booster. I think these technologies are exceedingly &lt;em&gt;interesting&lt;/em&gt;. The producers of LLMs are mostly untrustworthy, but the nuance has been lost. We usually don&amp;rsquo;t blame Facebook users when Meta does something shitty.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We exist in a dynamic period where challengers across domains could leverage AI against more lethargic incumbents. Civic and social good might result if good people would be willing to selectively wield AI in service of their desired outcomes. There&amp;rsquo;s plenty of reason to be angry at Meta, for example, but it doesn&amp;rsquo;t make sense to stubbornly refuse to use &lt;a href="https://www.llama.com/"&gt;Llama&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href="https://pytorch.org/"&gt;PyTorch&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href="https://ai.meta.com/sam3/"&gt;sam3&lt;/a&gt;, or React in pursuit of a better future.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Self-hosting Sustainably</title><link>https://subdavis.com/posts/2025-11-selfhosting/</link><pubDate>Sun, 16 Nov 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://subdavis.com/posts/2025-11-selfhosting/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;At some point, every home server operator loses steam. After 6+ years running ~20 applications on a home server, I wish only for things to work properly and not waste my time.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you&amp;rsquo;re anything like me, &lt;strong&gt;docker compose is probably all you need.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://github.com/subdavis/selfhosted"&gt;Here is my full configuration&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id="my-needs"&gt;My needs&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Any conversation about the &amp;ldquo;right&amp;rdquo; setup should be grounded in goals. These are mine.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;A bunch of network-reachable applications&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Some reachable over public internet&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Some behind SSO, IP Whitelist, or both&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Running as &lt;code&gt;&amp;lt;app&amp;gt;.subdavis.com&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Plus DNS filtering via AdGuardHome&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I no longer value arcane wisdom earned through &lt;a href="https://immich.app/cursed-knowledge"&gt;suffering&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id="10-year-old-hardware"&gt;10 year old hardware&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;An old 2010s Dell Optiplex Core i3, 8GB RAM&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Rehoused in a Fractal Design Node 304 Mini-ITX&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;With a 4TB media HDD&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;And a 2-Drive 2TB RAID-1 MDADM array for more important data&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;And another 1TB HDD for backups&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h2 id="everything-is-computer-docker-compose"&gt;Everything is &lt;del&gt;computer&lt;/del&gt; docker compose&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;My basic philosophy is that I should be able to get this junk running on new or reimaged hardware in a couple hours if needed. I can &lt;code&gt;apt dist-upgrade&lt;/code&gt; worry-free. Docker&amp;rsquo;s restart policy has never betrayed me the way &lt;a href="https://nosystemd.org/"&gt;systemd repeatedly has.&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id="a-little-bit-of-systemd-though"&gt;A little bit of systemd, though&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;systemd starts dockerd, which takes care of bringing up the compose stack on restart or container failure. Docker handles dependency constraints with grace.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;One extra need is for the external disks to be mounted properly before docker even tries to start. fstab can create race conditions, but systemd allows you to set mount dependencies on services, which is quite handy.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre tabindex="0"&gt;&lt;code class="language-conf" data-lang="conf"&gt;[Unit]
Description=RAID1

[Mount]
What=/dev/md0
Where=/media/primary
Type=ext4
Options=defaults,auto,noatime,exec

[Install]
WantedBy=docker.service
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;h2 id="traefik-is-whatever-man"&gt;Traefik is whatever, man&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I use &lt;a href="https://traefik.io/traefik"&gt;traefik&lt;/a&gt;. I learned it back when I had more energy for such things. I geniunely like its tag-based config because it keeps my &lt;code&gt;docker-compose.yml&lt;/code&gt; modular and clean, but traefik config is verbose and annoying to troubleshoot. If I were starting over today I might try &lt;a href="https://caddyserver.com/"&gt;caddy&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Still, the Letsencrypt support and Cloudflare companion have never let me down. Often, my new hostname has registered and is ready to serve traffic before the new app has even booted.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id="tired-of-fighting-dns"&gt;Tired of fighting DNS&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Maybe 6-8x per year, AdGuardHome goes down. Last year a slowly failing power supply lead to a lot of random system crashes. On this matter I have moved past depression to acceptance.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you, too, feel traumatized by &lt;code&gt;dhcp-option=6&lt;/code&gt;, I recommend giving up on your end user device discovery dreams and dealing with DNS at the router instead.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I run dnsmasq on my Edgerouter, redirect all DNS queries to my adguard instance wit NAT, and have a NAT rule enable/disable switch I can throw to take my AdGuardHome instance out of the critical path of internet access. &lt;a href="https://github.com/subdavis/selfhosted/blob/main/docs/pihole-dnsmasq.md"&gt;I wrote about that here.&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;(The NAT rule is necessary regardless of your config because plenty of IoT devices hard-code their DNS anyway. Looking at you, Philips Hue Bridge)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id="wireguard--tailscale-"&gt;Wireguard? 🙅 Tailscale? 👍&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Wireguard config has consumed many hours of my life. The final straw was tweaking MTU while dealing with packet loss over mobile networks (T Mobile). I noped out and set up Tailscale.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id="no-more-innovation-tokens"&gt;No more innovation tokens&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I started out using &lt;a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Container_Linux"&gt;CoreOS&lt;/a&gt; which turned out to be foolish because it was abandoned about 2 years later.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I also used to do &lt;a href="https://github.com/subdavis/selfhosted/blob/10f6aef418ffadcb3cefca16f3fad604abfb97a2/minio.service"&gt;insane, truly unhinged shit&lt;/a&gt; with &lt;code&gt;systemd&lt;/code&gt;. I believed that &lt;code&gt;docker compose&lt;/code&gt; was not a valid substitue for an init system, whatever that means. Don&amp;rsquo;t be like me.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Unnecessary complexity is fine for learning. A particular choice may emerge out of a desire for novelty or fun or curiosity, but be clear-eyed, lest you confuse these indulgences with actual improvements. It&amp;rsquo;s perfectly reasonable to tire of tinkering with complicated setups. Using docker compose isn&amp;rsquo;t admitting defeat.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Keep it simple, stupid.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>RSS - Really Simple Syndication</title><link>https://subdavis.com/posts/2025-11-rss-is-good/</link><pubDate>Sat, 08 Nov 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://subdavis.com/posts/2025-11-rss-is-good/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;Podcasts are nice. They show up in chronological order, download in the background, and work the same in every app. In a world of algorithmic walled garden social &amp;ldquo;platforms&amp;rdquo;, this is a small miracle.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Why can&amp;rsquo;t more of the internet be like that? As &lt;a href="https://www.theatlantic.com/ideas/archive/2023/03/social-media-algorithms-twitter-meta-rss-reader/673282/"&gt;Yair Rosenberg wrote in 2023&lt;/a&gt;, you can take back control of what you see on the internet.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id="its-just-rss"&gt;It&amp;rsquo;s just RSS&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The technology of a hopeful future actually came out in 1999. It&amp;rsquo;s just &lt;a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/RSS"&gt;RSS&lt;/a&gt;. Every morning I fire up &lt;a href="https://netnewswire.com/"&gt;NetNewsWire&lt;/a&gt;. I pick something, open it up, and read it. Nobody tracks me. There are no cookie policies to accept. There&amp;rsquo;s no like button or comment section.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In the days before profit motives overwhelmed product design, humans understood that the media you wanted to access had very little to do with the &amp;ldquo;platform&amp;rdquo; it was distributed by.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Imagine Youtube videos and Instagram comments and new issues of your local newsblog all just appear in one chronological feed. The obvious problem with all this control is that nobody can sell ads or harvest your personal data if you&amp;rsquo;re safe in your own third party app (Outside of a web browser! Offline, even!).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id="podcast-freedom-fleeting"&gt;Podcast freedom: fleeting&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Even podcasts may not have this freedom forever as companies try to capture the remaining frontier. The New York Times is taking steps to force listeners into their own app. Spotify made major plays in the last few years to get exclusive podcasts behind their paywall. Podcasters now implore that you watch their episodes on YouTube, where they can more effectively monetize and dissect a larger stream of analytic data. Eyeballs, baby.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It&amp;rsquo;s perfectly reasonable to want subscribers to pay for your content. Substack and Patreon are positive role models for how this should work: You give them cash and they give you an individualized subscription link to import the feed in your own app. The ads you hear are at the discretion of the creator, not the platform.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id="hunting-for-ghost-feeds"&gt;Hunting for ghost feeds&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Despite the incentives for companies to keep you on their site, looking at their ads and contributing to their engagement metrics, RSS doggedly persists. Idealistic developers have built RSS into most of the content management platforms (like Wordpress) that media use (mostly without paying). Some, like The Atlantic, even publish articles paywall-free, though the feeds are tough to find.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve been using a chrome extension called &lt;a href="https://chromewebstore.google.com/detail/get-rss-feed-url/kfghpdldaipanmkhfpdcjglncmilendn"&gt;Get RSS Feed URL&lt;/a&gt; that helps surface hidden feeds. It works in places you might not even expect, like Bluesky.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src="./bluesky.png" alt="it even works on bluesky"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id="conscious-of-content"&gt;Conscious of content&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Adopting an RSS-first means of consuming the web takes work, and the setup user experience can be rough. The exercise, though, can be enlightening. You might have a sense of how much &lt;em&gt;time&lt;/em&gt; you spend on your phone in a day, but where is that time spent?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The content of my media diet have changed a bit in the last 6 months since I went all-in on RSS. It took real effort, but now, when I open my phone, I reach for my RSS reader rather than a browser or a social app. It feels like an improvement.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>A few photos from Pittsburgh</title><link>https://subdavis.com/posts/2025-11-pittsburgh-photos/</link><pubDate>Tue, 04 Nov 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://subdavis.com/posts/2025-11-pittsburgh-photos/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;Photos from RandyLand, Bicycle Heaven, and around town in Pittsburgh, PA. October 2025.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>I want to get off Mr. Bones' Wild Ride</title><link>https://subdavis.com/posts/2025-11-introduction/</link><pubDate>Sat, 01 Nov 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://subdavis.com/posts/2025-11-introduction/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;In June of &amp;lsquo;25 I shut off most of my social media accounts: Facebook, Instagram, and LinkedIn. I kept reddit under the happy delusion that I could learn to use it responsibly (lol) but I&amp;rsquo;ve made strides to curtail that as well.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Since then, I&amp;rsquo;ve often thought about what the experience of being &amp;ldquo;on the internet&amp;rdquo; is like, and how that&amp;rsquo;s changed since I began forming digital habits back in High School. My memory is relatively poor, so a habit-forming tool for capturing a bit of life is wonderful. Having my good intentions packaged up to generate ad revenue and give teenagers an anxiety disorder is less so. &lt;a href="https://www.reuters.com/investigations/meta-is-earning-fortune-deluge-fraudulent-ads-documents-show-2025-11-06/"&gt;10% of Meta&amp;rsquo;s revenue for 2024 came from fraud.&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Still, I enjoy reading posts by people I&amp;rsquo;ll never meet. Putting stuff out into the world is fun. The &lt;a href="https://bearblog.dev/discover/"&gt;Bear Blog discover feed&lt;/a&gt; is usually pretty wholesome, HackerNews is still rockin&amp;rsquo;, and my RSS app is chock full of honest work by decent humans. In the near future I&amp;rsquo;d even like to recommend some of them.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The prevailing form and style of most social platforms lack honesty and curiosity.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item></channel></rss>