<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Posts on Brandon Davis</title><link>https://subdavis.com/posts/</link><description>Recent content in Posts on Brandon Davis</description><generator>Hugo</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Sat, 08 Nov 2025 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://subdavis.com/posts/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Really Simple Syndication, or RSS</title><link>https://subdavis.com/posts/rss-is-good/</link><pubDate>Sat, 08 Nov 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://subdavis.com/posts/rss-is-good/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;Podcasts are nice. They show up in chronological order, download in the background, and work the same in every app. In a world of algorithmic walled garden social &amp;ldquo;platforms&amp;rdquo;, this is a miracle.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Why can&amp;rsquo;t more of the internet be like that? As &lt;a href="https://www.theatlantic.com/ideas/archive/2023/03/social-media-algorithms-twitter-meta-rss-reader/673282/"&gt;Yair Rosenberg wrote in 2023&lt;/a&gt;, you can take back control of what you see on the internet.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id="its-just-rss"&gt;It&amp;rsquo;s just RSS&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The technology of a hopeful future actually came out in 1999. It&amp;rsquo;s just &lt;a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/RSS"&gt;RSS&lt;/a&gt;. Every morning I fire up NetNewsWire. God Himself cannot tamper with the sanctity or sort order of my feed. I pick something, open it up, and read it. Nobody tracks me. There are no cookie policies to accept. There&amp;rsquo;s no like button or comment section.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In the days before profit motives overwhelmed product design, humans understood that the media you wanted to access had very little to do with the &amp;ldquo;platform&amp;rdquo; it was distributed by.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Imagine Youtube videos and Instagram comments and new issues of your local newsblog all just appear in one chronological feed. The obvious problem with all this control is that nobody can sell ads or harvest your personal data if you&amp;rsquo;re safe in your own third party app (Outside of a web browser! Offline, even!).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;My preferred reader is &lt;a href="https://netnewswire.com/"&gt;NetNewsWire&lt;/a&gt; for iOS and MacOS.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id="podcast-freedom-fleeting"&gt;Podcast freedom: fleeting&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Even podcasts may not have this freedom forever as companies try to capture the remaining frontier. The New York Times is taking steps to force listeners into their own app. Spotify made major plays in the last few years to get exclusive podcasts behind their paywall. Podcasters now implore that you watch their episodes on YouTube, where they can more effectively monitize and dissect a larger stream of analytic data. Eyeballs, baby.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It&amp;rsquo;s perfectly reasonable to want subscribers to pay for your content. Substack and Patreon are positive role models for how this should work: You give them cash and they give you an individualized subscription link to import the feed in your own app. The ads you hear are at the discretion of the creator, not the platform.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id="hunting-for-ghost-feeds"&gt;Hunting for ghost feeds&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Despite the incentives for companies to keep you on their site, looking at their ads and contributing to their engagement metrics, RSS persists. Idealistic developers have built RSS into most of the content management platforms (like Wordpress) that media use (mostly without paying). Some, like The Atlantic, even publish articles paywall-free through difficult-to-find RSS feeds.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve been using a chrome extension called &lt;a href="https://chromewebstore.google.com/detail/get-rss-feed-url/kfghpdldaipanmkhfpdcjglncmilendn"&gt;Get RSS Feed URL&lt;/a&gt; that helps surface hidden feeds. It works in places you might not even expect, like Bluesky.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src="./bluesky.png" alt="it even works on bluesky"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Happy hunting.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>A few photos from Pittsburgh</title><link>https://subdavis.com/posts/2025-pittsburgh-photos/</link><pubDate>Tue, 04 Nov 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://subdavis.com/posts/2025-pittsburgh-photos/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;Photos from RandyLand, Bicycle Heaven, and around town in Pittsburgh, PA. October 2025.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>I want to get off Mr. Bones' Wild Ride</title><link>https://subdavis.com/posts/introduction/</link><pubDate>Sat, 01 Nov 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://subdavis.com/posts/introduction/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;In June of &amp;lsquo;25 I shut off most of my social media accounts: Facebook, Instagram, and LinkedIn. I kept reddit under the happy delusion that I could learn to use it responsibly (lol).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Since then, I&amp;rsquo;ve often thought about what the experience of being &amp;ldquo;on the internet&amp;rdquo; is like, and how that&amp;rsquo;s changed since I began forming digital habits back in High School. My memory is relatively poor, so a habit-forming tool for capturing a bit of life is wonderful. Having my good intentions packaged up to generate ad revenue and give teenagers an anxiety disorder is less so. &lt;a href="https://www.reuters.com/investigations/meta-is-earning-fortune-deluge-fraudulent-ads-documents-show-2025-11-06/"&gt;10% of Meta&amp;rsquo;s revenue for 2024 came from fraud.&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The early internet was beautiful, and like all beautiful things it was transformed by greed into dazzling technicolor sludge.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But still, I enjoy reading posts by people I&amp;rsquo;ll never meet. Putting stuff out into the world is fun. The &lt;a href="https://bearblog.dev/discover/"&gt;Bear Blog discover feed&lt;/a&gt; is usually pretty wholesome, HackerNews is still rockin&amp;rsquo;, and my RSS app is chock full of honest work by decent humans. In the near future I&amp;rsquo;d even like to recommend some of them.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The prevailing normal form and style of most social posts lack honesty and curiosity. Instagram is a posh bar I&amp;rsquo;m never properly dressed for.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I can dress how I want here 🙂&lt;/p&gt;</description></item></channel></rss>